# Bryan Sánchez Ortiz

San José, Costa Rica | (506) 83141411 | branbran911@hotmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/bryansanchez-ortiz/

#### **Profile**

Senior Full Stack Developer and Scrum Master. Graduated with honors Magna Cum Laude, impeccable research, time management and problem-solving skills, great team worker.

Dedicated to giving customers the best solutions to their software needs while functioning as a technical advisor with the idea making people's lives easier.

I've leaded multiple application projects for different companies, so I know my way around the entire lifecycle of an application and understand the requirements to build one. My experience is mostly with Microsoft technologies like .NET Core/C#

## **Objectives**

To seek challenging assignment and responsibility, with an opportunity for growth and career advancement as successful achievements.

#### Education

**Universidad Latina de Costa Rica**, San Pedro, San Jose, Costa Rica Systems Engineering, Graduated April 2014

**Universidad Estatal a Distancia**, Desamparados, San Jose, Costa Rica Systems Engineering and Project Management, Graduated November 2018

## **Experience**

### Aubrant Software, Heredia, Costa Rica

Senior Software Engineer, September 2020 – Current

- · Directed and developed software systems for a Metal Building construction company
- · Used .NET, Blazor and VueJS to plan, test, and implement various web-based applications.
- · Performed code reviews for other developers in order to meet the company standards.
- · Acted as a technical advisor, providing guidance on software development challenges.
- · Conducted interview processes for new team members.

### Fiserv, San Jose, Costa Rica

Senior Software Developer and Scrum Master, October 2016 – August 2020

- · Used Angular JS, Bootstrap, .Net and C# to design, test, and maintain various software for banking applications and fraud detection.
- · Acted as the Scrum Master for the team, providing guidance to maintain the development process.
- · Updated existing software to resolve issues and updated it to new business requirements.

## EX2 Outcoding, San Jose, Costa Rica

Software Developer, December 2015 – September 2016

- · Created custom reports using SQL and SSRS
- · Used C# to produce clean, tight code to create and upgrade web software applications.
- · Corrected errors to fix performance issues and improve usability.
- · Applied feedback from pull requests to deploy software up to the team standards

#### Crux Consultores, San Jose, Costa Rica

Software Developer, March 2015 – November 2015

- · Developed program logic for the costarican government bank
- · Produced clean, tight code based on SOLID principles.
- · Actively participated in the project lifecycle, including requirements gathering, design, coding and testing.
- · Managed integration and performing continual tests.

#### GBS Data Corporation, San Jose, Costa Rica

Web Developer, August 2014 – March 2015

- · Worked as a Front and Back-end web developer at RIsk Analysis department.
- · Directed the development of the company's internal website.
- · Lead a team of software engineers, fostering a collaborative and high-performing work environment.

#### Tek Experts, San Jose, Costa Rica

IT Support Engineer, August 2013 - July 2014

- · Gave support to users of a Project Management software from HP with SQL Server and Oracle databases.
- · Mentored the new team members and help with training and soft skills

#### Languages

Spanish: Native | English: Conversational

#### **Skills Summary:**

- .Net Framework, WebAPI, MVC
- C#, Visual Basic, Java, C++
- Blazor, VueJS, AngularJS
- REST web services
- MS SQL Server 2012+, Oracle 10,12,15,18,19 (PL/SQL), MySql
- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Telerik, MudBlazor, JSON, XML
- Git, Tortoise SVN, Subversion
- AWS, Azure
- Jira, TeamCity, TFS, Azure DevOps
- NUnit, Jest

## Other Education & Certifications

## **Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals**

Microsoft Credential
September 2024

## **Scrum Master Certified**

SCRUMstudy - Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile June 2019

# **Eset Security University**

IT Security online courses November 2013

# CENFOTEC

Web applications developing with HTML August 2010

### **CENFOTEC**

HTML5 and CSS3 January 2015